<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aws on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in aws on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 09:41:08 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.soudegesu.com/en/tags/aws/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Error 403 when accessing AWS IoT device shadow with Cognito authenticated user Identity</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/aws/access-iot-data-with-cognito-identity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 09:41:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/aws/access-iot-data-with-cognito-identity/</guid><description>AWS IoT is useful. You can manage and control the status of devices even remotely. On the other hand, mastering AWS IoT requires an understanding of the entire AWS IoT service, a familiarity with the not-so-friendly service console, and some tricky configuration. In this article, I will introduce some small AWS IoT tips. Goals Getting AWS IoT Device Shadows in Mobile Apps Only authenticated users can access device shadows Use</description></item><item><title>Provisioning a edge device in a private network with Ansible via AWS Session Manager</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/aws/provisioning-with-ansible-via-ssm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 15:12:06 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/aws/provisioning-with-ansible-via-ssm/</guid><description>In this article, I will show you how to access devices in a private network in a remote location to manage the device configuration by AWS System Manager Session Manager and Ansible. Device provisioning in a private network I would like to run a configuration management script from my development machine at home on a remotely located device. The image is as follows. In most cases, the remotely located devices</description></item><item><title>Install Docker to Amazon Linux2</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/amazonlinux2-docker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/amazonlinux2-docker/</guid><description>Migration of Amazon Linux to Amazon Linux 2 causes yum install docker command doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in Amazon Linux 2, so I investigate how to install docker.
Motivation Install Docker to Amazon Linux2 without error My Packer build job stopped with error after AWS announced Amazon Linux 2 LTS Candidate in June 2018, because I migrated my server os Amazon Linux to Amazon Linux2.
Fail to execute yum install docker and yum search docker command because yum repository has been changed.</description></item><item><title>Add partitions periodically in AWS RDS Aurora Cluster (MySQL compatible) with the SQL Procedures</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/rds-aurora-cluster-partitioning-procedure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/rds-aurora-cluster-partitioning-procedure/</guid><description>Introduction RDS Aurora is a managed service provided by AWS. Aurora is a OSS compatible relational database built on cloud.
In this article, I explain table partitioning with date in RDS Aurora MySQL compatible.
Goals Create table partitioned by date on RDS Aurora (MySQL compatible) Add a partition for a day periodically (once a day) Drop records after a certain period of time Handle errors in these operation running As an example, I handle the following hoge table.</description></item><item><title>It's better to use DNS verification for verification of SSL certificate issued by AWS Certification Manager</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/validate-certification-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/validate-certification-manager/</guid><description>Domain verification with Route 53 in Certification Manager became available In November 2017, Domain validation by DNS records of Route 53 was supported as a verification method when AWS Certification Manager(ACM) SSL certificate was acquired. This update has a very great advantage not only for acquiring SSL certificates but also for updating SSL certificates.
Changes in issuing SSL certificates Validation by email is troublesome Conventionally, in order to verify the domain of SSL certificate at ACM, we click on the link in the body of the received email, and push the approval button in the web page.</description></item></channel></rss>