<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/categories/docker/</link><description>Recent content in docker on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 14:28:08 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.soudegesu.com/en/categories/docker/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Prometheus, Grafana and pushgateway cluster with Kubernates</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/docker/prometheus-on-kubernates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 14:28:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/docker/prometheus-on-kubernates/</guid><description>This article is my notes on practicing building a cluster of Prometheus, Grafana and pushgateway in Kubernates environment. The repository is located at soudegesu/prometheus-pushgw-practice . Goals Building a Prometheus, Grafana and pushgateway cluster with Kubernates Grafana references Prometheus as a datasource. Prometheus pull metrics from pushgateway. For now, I will aim to build a cluster on a local machine. These goals outline is as shown in the following figure. Environment</description></item><item><title>Start mysql docker container with docker-compose</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/docker/docker-compose/mysql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/docker/docker-compose/mysql/</guid><description>In the previous article, I can start mysql docker container by using the docker run command after executing docker build.
Personally, I like the lesser option of cli, so this time I'd like to start docker-compose a bit easier to start up.
Install docker-compose Let's install docker-toolbox from the following site. Docker-compose is also included in the download.
https://docs.docker.com/toolbox/ Docker-compose provides functions to easily manage multiple containers. In this article, only mysql is started with a container, but since setting up system components and controlling the order of activation can only be described in yaml file, it is highly readable and easy to manage even with VCS.</description></item><item><title>Create a Docker image with docker build command</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/docker/image/build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/docker/image/build/</guid><description>This post is a personal note for building mysql container using Docker.
Update Docker daemon In my case, the version of docker was old, so I downloaded docker for Mac from the official website and updated docker daemon.
Check docker version.
1docker version 2 3Client: 4 Version: 1.13.0 5 API version: 1.25 6 Go version: go1.7.3 7 Git commit: 49bf474 8 Built: Wed Jan 18 16:20:26 2017 9 OS/Arch: darwin/amd64 10 11Server: 12 Version: 1.</description></item></channel></rss>