<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in docker on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 14:28:08 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.soudegesu.com/en/tags/docker/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Prometheus, Grafana and pushgateway cluster with Kubernates</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/docker/prometheus-on-kubernates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 14:28:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/docker/prometheus-on-kubernates/</guid><description>This article is my notes on practicing building a cluster of Prometheus, Grafana and pushgateway in Kubernates environment. The repository is located at soudegesu/prometheus-pushgw-practice . Goals Building a Prometheus, Grafana and pushgateway cluster with Kubernates Grafana references Prometheus as a datasource. Prometheus pull metrics from pushgateway. For now, I will aim to build a cluster on a local machine. These goals outline is as shown in the following figure. Environment</description></item><item><title>Install Docker to Amazon Linux2</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/amazonlinux2-docker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/aws/amazonlinux2-docker/</guid><description>Migration of Amazon Linux to Amazon Linux 2 causes yum install docker command doesn't work in Amazon Linux 2, so I investigate how to install docker.
Motivation Install Docker to Amazon Linux2 without error My Packer build job stopped with error after AWS announced Amazon Linux 2 LTS Candidate in June 2018, because I migrated my server os Amazon Linux to Amazon Linux2.
Fail to execute yum install docker and yum search docker command because yum repository has been changed.</description></item><item><title>Create a Docker image with docker build command</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/docker/image/build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/docker/image/build/</guid><description>This post is a personal note for building mysql container using Docker.
Update Docker daemon In my case, the version of docker was old, so I downloaded docker for Mac from the official website and updated docker daemon.
Check docker version.
1docker version 2 3Client: 4 Version: 1.13.0 5 API version: 1.25 6 Go version: go1.7.3 7 Git commit: 49bf474 8 Built: Wed Jan 18 16:20:26 2017 9 OS/Arch: darwin/amd64 10 11Server: 12 Version: 1.</description></item></channel></rss>