<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 10:54:40 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.soudegesu.com/en/tags/python/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use PyPDF2 - open PDF file or encrypted PDF file</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/open-pdf-with-pypdf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 10:54:40 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/open-pdf-with-pypdf/</guid><description>Motivation Since I want to work PDF file with Python on my work, I investigate what library can do that and how to use it. Preparation The runtime and module version are as below. python 3.6 PyPDF2 1.26.0 Install PyPDF2 To work PDF file with Python, PyPDF2 is often used. PyPDF2 can Extract text from PDF file Work existing PDF file and create new one Let&amp;rsquo;s install with pip command.</description></item><item><title>Use openpyxl - Convert to DataFrame in Pandas</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/pandas-with-openpyxl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 06:52:26 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/pandas-with-openpyxl/</guid><description>Introduction Previously, I wrote several articles on working Excel files using openpyxl. Use openpyxl - open, save Excel files in Python Use openpyxl - create a new Worksheet, change sheet property in Python Use openpyxl - read and write Cell in Python In this article, I introduce how to convert openpyxl data to Pandas data format called DataFrame. Preparation Install modules First, install module with pip command. 1pip install openpyxl</description></item><item><title>Use openpyxl - read and write Cell in Python</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/cell-excel-with-openpyxl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 09:38:14 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/cell-excel-with-openpyxl/</guid><description>Introduction In previous article, &amp;ldquo;Use openpyxl - create a new Worksheet, change sheet property in Python&amp;rdquo;, I introduced how to create a new Worksheet and change Worksheet properties. In this article I show how to read and write Cell in Excel with Python. Enter values to Cell Worksheet object has a position of Cell as property. That is dictionary type and consists of row and column number. Using them, access</description></item><item><title>Use openpyxl - create a new Worksheet, change sheet property in Python</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/sheet-excel-with-openpyxl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 08:53:18 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/sheet-excel-with-openpyxl/</guid><description>Introduction In previous article, I showed how to create a new Excel file with openpyxl in Python. In this article, I create a new Worksheet, change sheet property Excel files in Python. Environment Runtime environment is as below. python 3.6 openpyxl 2.5.6 Create a new Worksheet Use create_sheet function to add new Worksheet. 1from openpyxl.workbook import Workbook 2 3wb = Workbook() 4 5ws1 = wb.create_sheet(&amp;#34;Sheet_A&amp;#34;) 6ws1.title = &amp;#34;Title_A&amp;#34; 7 8ws2</description></item><item><title>Use openpyxl - open, save Excel files in Python</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/create-excel-with-openpyxl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 18:34:52 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/post/python/create-excel-with-openpyxl/</guid><description>Introduction In this article I show how to work Excel with openpyxl. Environment Runtime environment is as below. python 3.6 openpyxl 2.5.6 Install Use openpyxl. The openpyxl official document says .. openpyxl is a Python library to read/write Excel 2010 xlsx/xlsm/xltx/xltm files. However, openpyxl can also work with Mac Excel 2016 on my Macbook Pro. Let&amp;rsquo;s install with pip command. 1pip install openpyxl Create new Excel file Import openpyxl At</description></item><item><title>Google Colaboratory is the best tool for machine learning engineer</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/colaboratory-is-a-good-tool-for-tensorflow-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/colaboratory-is-a-good-tool-for-tensorflow-user/</guid><description>For engineer who use Jupyter Notebook in often, web IDE named Colaboratory is the best tool. Try Colaboratory.
What is Colaboratory? Colaboratory is a web IDE based on Jupyter notebook and hosted by Google.
Not only editor, but also runtime is provided by Google, users don&amp;rsquo;t need to create the environment for development.
Everyone can use Colaboratory without Google account, however, links the account, users earn lots of advantages.</description></item><item><title>Convert a string representing the date or epoch time to datetime and change timezone in Python</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/python-datetime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/python-datetime/</guid><description>Motivation Because I always google the way to convert a string representing the date to datetime and change timezone on the Internet, this is note to self article.
There are three types to process date and time in Python. datetime, date, and time. I mainly use datetime in this article.
Environment python 3.6 pytz jupyter notebook Convert epoch time to datetime Now convert numeric data types of eopch time to datetime.</description></item><item><title>Setting to avoid python and anaconda conflict using pyenv and pyenv-virtualenv</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/pyenv/anaconda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/pyenv/anaconda/</guid><description>Introduction I have been using pyenv only to switch versions of python in local environments. However, recently I use anaconda more often. Since python and anaconda conflict when executing activate command, I decided to use pyenv-virtualenv.
Goals Switch python version in one machine Switch the python distribution (anaconda in this case) Resolve conflict between anaconda and pyenv when I execute activate command Activate anaconda without executing the command with full path Both 1 and 2 above are able to solved with pyenv and 3 with pyenv-virtualent.</description></item></channel></rss>