<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/categories/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Sou-Nan-De-Gesu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.soudegesu.com/en/categories/python/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Colaboratory is the best tool for machine learning engineer</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/colaboratory-is-a-good-tool-for-tensorflow-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/colaboratory-is-a-good-tool-for-tensorflow-user/</guid><description>For engineer who use Jupyter Notebook in often, web IDE named Colaboratory is the best tool. Try Colaboratory.
What is Colaboratory? Colaboratory is a web IDE based on Jupyter notebook and hosted by Google.
Not only editor, but also runtime is provided by Google, users don&amp;rsquo;t need to create the environment for development.
Everyone can use Colaboratory without Google account, however, links the account, users earn lots of advantages.</description></item><item><title>Convert a string representing the date or epoch time to datetime and change timezone in Python</title><link>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/python-datetime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.soudegesu.com/en/python/python-datetime/</guid><description>Motivation Because I always google the way to convert a string representing the date to datetime and change timezone on the Internet, this is note to self article.
There are three types to process date and time in Python. datetime, date, and time. I mainly use datetime in this article.
Environment python 3.6 pytz jupyter notebook Convert epoch time to datetime Now convert numeric data types of eopch time to datetime.</description></item></channel></rss>